<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blockchain on Yijia Chen</title><link>https://yijiachen.me/tags/blockchain/</link><description>Recent content in blockchain on Yijia Chen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 15:01:41 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yijiachen.me/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fully On-Chain Game</title><link>https://yijiachen.me/posts/on-chain-game/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 15:01:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://yijiachen.me/posts/on-chain-game/</guid><description>A few specific thoughts, which are not fully formed nor validated, about fully on-chain games and their future.
Fully on-chain games (FOCG), as a standalone category, are vastly more different from play-to-earn (P2E) games like Axie than P2E games from traditional, web2 games. This is because neither converting all ownable objects into freely tradable NFTs, nor launching a game token representing the ecosystem and participation value, impose real constraints on the game system/logic itself.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Virtual Worlds</title><link>https://yijiachen.me/posts/virtual-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 09:13:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://yijiachen.me/posts/virtual-world/</guid><description>With credits to Kevin Zhang, the Dark Forest team, and guiltygyoza.
First, defining what I mean by a virtual world. A virtual world is an alternative world to the physical one we live in, one with possibly different physical and emergent laws, in which a human can develop interesting experiences.
Why They Are Interesting&amp;nbsp;¶ The Matrix is one of the most loved and provocative movie series of all time. In the movies, one scene I remember particularly well: When Neo is first taken into The Matrix by Morpheus, the two of them have a martial fight in a Kung Fu arena.</description></item></channel></rss>